# Francis Xirui Yang

Tech and business savvy, proactive, detail oriented and responsible. Software Engineer (2017 New Graduate of UCSC) dedicated to building services and applications that promote ultimate quality and user experience. izayacity@gmail.com +1(669)264-9019 Santa Clara, CA, US https://izayacity.github.io/

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# TO-ON KIKAKU CO.,LTD (株式会社東音企画)

11/2015 - 02/2016

Software Engineer Intern

Tokyo, Japan

- Contributed the development of lesson-time.com and its mobile app, a piano education system.
- Assisted non-tech coworkers to monitor the server by developing a backend middleware independently.
- Visualized server usage and optimized 1000+ SQL and GQL reading from 40s to <1s by Memcache.</li>
- (PHP | JavaScript | Go | Slim | Ionic | Bootstrap | AJAX | GAE | Datastore | Memcache | MySQL | REST APIs)

**NSFOCUS INC.** 11/2014 – 04/2015

Software Development Engineer Intern in Test

Beijing, China

- Systematized device reservation process by developing a lab management system using Python Django.
- Created auto-test Python scripts instead of previous manually checking 7000+ rules for 2 weeks.
- Contributed IPS hardware test and development at data center and coordinated with 4 departments.
- (Python | Django | C++ | jQuery | HTML | Regex | Snort | Linux | VMware | Excel | Bugzilla | UML | SSH)

## **EDUCATION**

## UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SANTA CRUZ

09/2016 - 09/2017

M.Sc. in Games and Playable Media of Computational Media, GPA: 3.67 / 4.0

# BEIJING UNIVERSITY OF POSTS AND TELECOMMUNICATIONS

B.Eng. in Network Engineering of Computer Science, GPA: 3.2 / 4.0

California, USA 09/2011 - 07/2015 Beijing, China

#### **PROJECTS**

## Online Card Game (HearthStone-style, solo without support)

06/2017 - 08/2017

- Architected the tech stack and made weekly plans, reports, scrum (using Trello) and code reviews.
- Designed and developed <u>JSON-RPC APIs on GitLab</u> and a <u>jQuery</u> networking testing tool that enabled continuous development instead of re-building 2 clients locally.
- Solved WebSocket communication, threading, runtime instantiation, coroutine challenges and deployed the server onto Docker container and AWS ECS cluster for scaling and enabling multiple game sessions.
- (NodeJS | ExpressJS | Unity C# | Socket.IO | WebSocket | jQuery | Docker | AWS ECS)

## Tornado Tower Game (VR Platformer on Oculus, exhibited on E3 2017)

01/2017 - 06/2017

- Made tech solutions, impacted team decisions and optimized dev processes resulting in the team's
  progress ahead of competitors in the program, as Lead Programmer of <u>Dizzy Slugs</u>, a team of 10+ people.
- Implemented gameplay such as traps, enemies, file data system, audio, etc, using Unreal Engine 4.
- Managed the team to use Git tools, led and ensured branch merging and maintained AWS Route53.

## **SKILLS AND INTERESTS**

**TECH:** C++ | JavaScript | C# | PHP | Go | Java | Python | NodeJS | Ionic | RESTful APIs | GraphQL | Unity | UE4 | AWS | Google App Engine | SQL | NoSQL | Linux | Docker | HTML/CSS | Memcache | MVC | Git | Agile

LANGUAGES: English: Fluent | Chinese: Fluent | Japanese: Intermediate (with JLPT N3 Certificate)

INTERESTS: Tech | Business | Gaming | Anime | Soccer | Foreign Culture | Social Events | Outdoor

For more information and other projects, please check out my portfolio website at <a href="https://izayacity.github.io/">https://izayacity.github.io/</a>.